{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a mortar, the binding material is", "opta": "cement", "optb": "sand", "optc": "surkhi", "optd": "cinder.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lacquer paints", "opta": "are generally applied on structural steel", "optb": "are less durable as compared to enamel paints", "optc": "consist of resin and nitro-cellulose", "optd": "contain alcohol as thinner", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wrought iron contains carbon upto", "opta": "0.25%", "optb": "1.0%", "optc": "1.5%", "optd": "2%.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the polymineralic rock from the following:", "opta": "Quartz sand", "optb": "Pure gypsum", "optc": "Magnesite", "optd": "Granite", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "For thin structures subjected to wetting and drying, the water cement ratio should be 0.45", "optb": "For mass concrete structures subjected to wetting and drying, the water ratio should be 0.55", "optc": "For thin structures which remain continuously under water, the water-cement ratio by weight should be 0.55", "optd": "For massive concrete structures which remain continuously under water, the water cement ratio by weight should be 0.65", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ultimate strength to cement is provided by", "opta": "Tricalcium silicate", "optb": "Di-calcium silicate", "optc": "Tri-calcium aluminate", "optd": "Tetra calcium alumino ferrite.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Elastomers can extend upto", "opta": "five times their original dimensions", "optb": "seven times their original dimensions", "optc": "ten times their original dimensions", "optd": "three times their original dimensions.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bitumen felt", "opta": "is used as water proofing material", "optb": "is used as damp proofing material", "optc": "is made from bitumen and hessian fibres", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In   the   method   of   condensation polymerization,", "opta": "low-molecular substances are removed from the high molecular substance", "optb": "the reaction proceeds with an evolution of ammonia", "optc": "the reaction proceeds with an evolution of hydrogen chloride", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the cement the compound quickest to react with water, is", "opta": "Tricalcium aluminate", "optb": "Tetra-calcium alumino-ferrite", "optc": "Tricalcium silicate", "optd": "Dicalcium silicate.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The initial setting time of lime-pozzolana, is", "opta": "30 minutes", "optb": "60 minutes", "optc": "90 minutes", "optd": "120 minutes.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The clay to be used for manufacturing bricks for a large project, is dugout and allowed to weather throughout", "opta": "the monsoon", "optb": "the winter", "optc": "the summer", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rocks which are formed due to cooling of magma at a considerable depth from earth's surface are called", "opta": "Plutonic rocks", "optb": "Hypabyssal rocks", "optc": "Volcanic rocks", "optd": "Igneous rocks.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Quartzite is a", "opta": "metamorphic rock", "optb": "argillaceous rock", "optc": "calcareous rock", "optd": "silicious rock.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The variety of pig iron used for manufacture of wrought iron, is", "opta": "Bessemer pig", "optb": "Grey or foundry pig", "optc": "White forge pig", "optd": "Mottled pig.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sand stone is", "opta": "sedimentary rock", "optb": "metamorphic rock", "optc": "igneous rock", "optd": "volcanic rock.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the furnace is provided with insufficient fuel at low temperatures, the type of pig iron produced, is called", "opta": "Bessemer pig", "optb": "Grey or foundry pig", "optc": "White or forge pig", "optd": "Mottled pig.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stainless steel contains", "opta": "18% of chromuim and 8% nickel", "optb": "8% of chromium and 18% of nickel", "optc": "12% of chromium and 36% of nickel", "optd": "36% of chromium and 12% of nickel.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the hypabyssal rock from the following:", "opta": "Granite", "optb": "Dolerite", "optc": "Basalt", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Depending on the chemical composition and mechanical properties, iron may be classified as", "opta": "cast iron", "optb": "wrought iron", "optc": "steel", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wrought iron contains carbon about", "opta": "1.5% to 5.5%", "optb": "0.5% to 1.75%", "optc": "0.1% to 0.25%", "optd": "none to these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main constituent of fly-ash, is", "opta": "aluminium oxide", "optb": "silica", "optc": "ferrous oxide", "optd": "All of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bitumen in", "opta": "solid state, is called asphalt", "optb": "semi fluid state, is called mineral tar", "optc": "fluid state, is called petroleum", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plastics made from cellulose resin", "opta": "are as clear as glass", "optb": "are tough and strong", "optc": "possess excellent electrical properties", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Kaolin is chemically classified as", "opta": "metamorphic rock", "optb": "argillaceous rock", "optc": "calcareous rock", "optd": "silicious rock.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is acid resistant asbestos:", "opta": "actinolite asbestos", "optb": "amosite asbestos", "optc": "anthophylite asbestos", "optd": "crocidolite asbestos", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Due to attack of dry rot, the timber", "opta": "cracks", "optb": "shrinks", "optc": "reduces to powder", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Brittleness of cold is due to an excess of", "opta": "sulphur", "optb": "carbon", "optc": "phosphorus", "optd": "silicon.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the manufacture of Portland cement, the proportions of raw materials used, are", "opta": "lime 63% ; silica 22% ; other ingredients 15%", "optb": "lime 22% ; silica 63% ; other ingredients 15%", "optc": "silica 40% ; lime 40% ; other ingredients 20%", "optd": "silica 70% ; lime 20% ; other ingredients 10%.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Asbestos cement", "opta": "is brittle", "optb": "warps due to changes in humidity", "optc": "strength is lowered when saturated by water", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gniess is obtained from", "opta": "igneous rocks", "optb": "metamorphic rocks", "optc": "sedimentary rocks", "optd": "sedimentary metamorphic rocks.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rocks formed by gradual deposition, are called", "opta": "sedimentary rocks", "optb": "igneous rocks", "optc": "metamorphic rocks", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Galvanising means covering iron with a thin coat of", "opta": "tin", "optb": "zinc", "optc": "glaze", "optd": "coal tar.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For preparing porcelains, the clay should be", "opta": "sufficiently pure", "optb": "of high degree of tanacity", "optc": "of good plasticity", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polymerization helps to improve the property of", "opta": "strength", "optb": "rigidity", "optc": "elasticity", "optd": "all of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Good quality stones must", "opta": "be durable", "optb": "be free from clay", "optc": "resist action of acids", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sewer pipes are made of", "opta": "earthen ware", "optb": "stone ware", "optc": "refractory clay", "optd": "terracota", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fibre glass", "opta": "retains heat-longer", "optb": "has a higher strength to weight ratio", "optc": "is shock proof and fire retardent", "optd": "does not decay", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The theory of formation of concrete is based on the phenomena of formation of voids", "optb": "The bulking of sand is taken into account while volumetric proportioning of the aggregates", "optc": "The dry sand and the sand completely flooded with water, have practically the same volume", "optd": "The expansion and contraction joints are provided if concrete structures exceed 12 m in length", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "In stone arches, the stones are placed with their natural beds radial", "optb": "In cornices, the stones are placed with their natural beds as vertical", "optc": "In stone walls, the stones are placed with their natural beds as horizontal", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonly used colour pigment in paints, is", "opta": "ambers", "optb": "carbon black", "optc": "iron oxide", "optd": "lamp black", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Varnish is a transparent or semi-transparent solution of resinuous substances in", "opta": "alcohol", "optb": "linseed", "optc": "turpentine", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Initial setting time of cement for asbestos cement products should be not less than", "opta": "30 minutes", "optb": "50 minutes", "optc": "75 minutes", "optd": "90 minutes.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The variety of pig iron used for the manufacture of steel by Bessemer process, is", "opta": "Bessemer pig", "optb": "Grey pig", "optc": "White forge pig", "optd": "Mottled pig.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For melting one tonne of cast iron", "opta": "700 m3 air is required", "optb": "20 kg limestone is required", "optc": "one quintal coke is required", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For filling cracks in masonry structures, the type of bitumen used, is", "opta": "cut-back bitumen", "optb": "bitumen-emulsion", "optc": "blown bitumen", "optd": "plastic bitumen.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plastic", "opta": "is an organic substance", "optb": "consists of natural or synthetic binders", "optc": "finished products are rigid and stable at normal temperature", "optd": "is capable of flow when necessary heat and pressure are applied", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vanadium steel is generally used for", "opta": "railway switches and crossing", "optb": "bearing balls", "optc": "magnets", "optd": "axles and springs.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "In basic Bessemer process, the steel heats the converter", "optb": "In open-hearth process, the furnace heats the steel", "optc": "In Siemens process, the impurities of pig iron are oxidised by the oxygen of the ore", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of manufacturing steel by heating short lengths of wrought iron bars mixed with charcoal in fire clay crucibles and collecting the molten iron into moulds, is known as", "opta": "Cementation process", "optb": "Crucible process", "optc": "Bessemer process", "optd": "Open hearth process.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}